现在你已经写下自己的句子，试着在母语中
Now that you've written your sentence down, try shifting the stress around in
通过不同重音模式来移动重音。不要刻意模仿某种
your own language by going through the stress patterns. Don't try to put on a
美式或其他口音，只要每次说句子时重读不同的词。
particular American or other accent. Just concentrate on stressing a different word
例如，如果你的语言是德语，
in the sentence each time you say it. For example, if your language is German, ich
例如这句德语，你会改变重音位置。
habe nicht gesagt, dass er das Geld gestohlen hat, you would change the stress
to, ich habe nicht gesagt, dass er das Geld gestohlen
如果把它翻译成法语，你会说：
If you translated it into French, you would say,
或者：
Or,
在日语里，很多人认为没有语调变化，但如果你听到
In Japanese, many people think there are no intonation changes, but if you hear
有人这样说，就会意识到它和其他语言一样，也有相似之处。
someone say, you'll realize that it has similarities to every other language.
或者：
Or,
不管这对你来说听起来多奇怪，都要在母语中把每个不同的词重读几遍。
No matter how strange it may sound to you, stress each different word several times
你可能会注意到，有些词听起来很正常，
in your language. You may notice that with some words it sounds perfectly normal, but
而另一些词会听起来非常奇怪。或者你可能会发现，在你的语言里，
with other words it sounds very strange. Or you may find that in your language,
如果你更喜欢改变词序或替换另一个词，而不是重读某个词，
rather than stressing a word, you prefer to change the word order or substitute
换另一个词。无论怎么做都可以，只要你意识到自己的语言模式
another word. Whatever you do is fine, as long as you realize where your language
这些模式与美式英语的语调模式既有相似之处，也有不同之处。
patterns are similar to and different from the American English intonation patterns.
这样，当你再用英语做同样练习时，就会容易得多。注意：一个很好的
Then, when you do it again in English, it'll be much easier. Note, an excellent
练习，是用美式口音来说你的母语。
exercise is to practice speaking your native language with an American accent.
如果你能听起来像美国人在说你的母语，想象一下，
If you can sound like an American speaking your native language, imagine how easy it
用美式口音说英语会变得多容易。练习在母语中移动
would be to speak English with an American accent. Practice shifting the stressed
重读词。
words in your native language.